whether or not you have enough space for
a dedicated home gym adjustable
dumbbells are arguably the most
practical piece of equipment you could
purchase regarding strength building
because they're going to save you a
whole lot of space as opposed to
purchasing a full set of traditional
dumbbells and a storage rack but they're
also going to save you you know a chunk
of change as well now a question we get
a lot with pretty much all equipment but
talking about adjustable dumbbells here
is which ones are the best it could be a
lot you know there's a lot of different
options out there and you definitely
need to be really smart when it comes to
finding the best ones for you
specifically so guess what that's what
I'm here to do today we're going to talk
about the best adjustable dumbbells that
are on the
[Music]
market what's up everybody it's Jake
back in the barbing garage gym and for
today's video we're going to talk about
the best adjustable dumbbells that are
on the market since this is you know a
decently long video and I know why
you're here it's to find out which one
is the best why don't I just go ahead
and tell you it's the new Bells honestly
you know when it comes to the ease of
use the available weight and the
materials these just really get the job
done especially since the plastic is
kept to a minimum now I'm going to
expand on why we're so high on these
dumbbells in just a second but I just
want to make sure youall know that we're
talking about some other categories as
well you we're going to talk about best
for beginners best for a budget and a
few more but one more quick thing before
I go any further we also have an article
that pairs with this video and you
definitely should go check that out all
you got to do is search barbend best
adjustable dumbbells and it's going to
pull right up for you okay so let's get
back to the new o bells and start
talking about what I really like about
them and let's talk about ease of use
first all right so the class classic you
know loadable dumbbells where you just
have you know your handle and you put a
dumbbell on and then you kind of you
know screw it in and keep it secured
that takes forever to do and so you know
adjustable dumbbells in general have you
know really you know improved in that
regard but this technology right here is
just incredible to me all you do is just
twist the handle and you're flying
through the available weight speaking of
available weight there's two different
options with the newells you can get the
50 lb pair or the 80lb pair that we have
these are going to range from 5 to 50 or
5 to 80 in 5 lb increments so there's
plenty of weight for you to work with
and 80 lbs is honestly pretty heavy most
you know average adjustable dumbbells
they're starting to get a little heavier
nowadays but you know generally speaking
most adjustable dumbbells cap out right
around 50 to 55 lbs so if you go for the
80 lbs specifically it's going to allow
you to really you know grow and expand
you know within your workouts and with
your strength level and everything like
that now when it comes to the materials
you know once again plastic is kept to a
minimum now you know this adjustment
mechanism in here yes there's some
plastic and there's some plastic used to
hold the heads of the dumbbell you know
to the handles handle itself so
definitely keep that in mind this isn't
something you want to just Chuck and
drop you know people tend to drop
dumbbells traditional dumbbells whenever
they're working out with them it's not
really something I'd recommend doing
here but they're still going to be able
to handle you know the occasional you
know drop and you know some bumps and
bruise and everything like that now one
thing that I got to mention is that
these are pretty pricey okay so these 80
lb dumbbells you know before shipping
and taxes and everything they're going
to run you right around $800 you know
after that it's close to a th000
especially if you go after the optional
stand which is you know extra $100 $110
or something like that so definitely
keep that in mind they're definitely a
little bit pricey but when it comes to
you know checking off pretty much every
single box that you could imagine the
new o Bells just simply get the job
done
[Music]
okay so these next dumbbells honestly
hold a special place in my heart that's
because of how surprisingly good they
are and we actually went ahead and gave
them two separate Awards and I'm talking
about the Nordic Track selecta weights
Nord track is obviously known for their
cardio equipment but honestly y'all they
absolutely crushed it with these
dumbbells so the first word I want to
talk about is the most versatile these
are the most versatile adjustable
dumbbells and that's basically because
of the different increments you have to
work with all right so you have 2 and
1/2 PB increments to work with 5 lb
increments to work with but I've also
been using 7 and 1/2 lbs now I don't
have an issue with it it feels pretty
balanced but that 7 and 1/2 might get a
little tricky for some people because
you you have some change plates I guess
you could call them on either side and
you that's where you get the two and a
half and 5 PBS all all by you know
selecting it and using the little slider
right here so it might be a little funky
at first but honestly it works great for
me it's probably going to work great for
you too and you know having these little
micro increments to you know go up in is
really crucial with dumbbells in general
because you're doing a lot of isolated
movements doing a lot of lateral raises
overhead tricep extensions even curls if
you want I mean just name it having
those small little jumps in weight
really goes a long way and you know not
every other dumbbell out there has that
much versatility within it when it comes
to adjusting so that's pretty sweet
second award we're giving these is best
for beginners and that's because you
know so technically these are 50 lbs but
with the extra five you can add on each
side that's 60 so that's plenty of
weight you can still you know grow with
as you're you know really getting into
your fitness journey also these only
going to cost you 400 bucks now they
used to be 350 gone up a little bit
probably because of the popularity but
400 bucks for these you get a steel
handle here it's still knurled there is
some plastic there's more plastic mix
mixed in right here than these other
ones but it's still kind of kept at a
minimum you know it's right here with
this selector pin on the inside and
these little like change plates I was
talking about those are plastic but
there's still a good amount of Steel
here so honestly y'all 400 bucks 60 lb
you got all that versatility these are
just really
[Music]
sweet okay so this next award goes out
to my heavy LIF out there and we're
talking about the snowed ad80 drop proof
adjustable dumbbells all right so real
quick yes I know that there are some
other adjustable dumbbells that get
heavier than 80 lb but you know as you
start to kind of go up and weight like
that a lot of times you lose quality and
we prioritize quality here at barbend
and that's something that you're
definitely getting with these right here
okay so ease of use is another thing as
well right as I talked about with the
new Bells earlier all you got to do to
adjust the weight here on these
dumbbells is just simply twist this
little knob right here and you're going
to fly through the available weight so
these are the 80 lbs they have 50 lb
pair as well only thing only you know
drawback I have with these is that it's
10 lb increments you do not have 5B
increments so you're kind of forced to
go and purchase their magnetic weights
you're going to get four of them there's
1.25 lb each and you know essentially
you can get these up to 85 lb which is
for the average home gym owner for
really for average athlete a lot of
athletes 85 lbs is pretty much plenty of
weight right now if you wanted to do
some you know heavy squats with some
dumbbells just hold both of them and you
got you know over 160 lbs right there so
that's pretty cool now there's also very
minimal plastic used here right this is
pretty much all metal and steel the only
plastic you're going to find is right
here with this adjustment mechanism I
mean even the stand right here is steel
which is something that I cannot say
about any of these other dumbbells right
here now because of all of that the
quality and everything these are also
going to run you around $800 before
shipping and everything like that so
definitely keep that in mind but because
of the durability and the minimal
plastic used you can drop these
adjustable dumbbells from 32 in when it
comes to heavy lifting some adjustable
dumbbells snows take the
cake
[Music]
now when it comes to the best overall
value we're actually giving that nod to
the ativa fit adjustable dumbbells all
right so these are their 66 lb pair
these going to cost you right around 400
bucks which is a pretty solid deal
they're going to replace 12 individual
pairs of traditional dumbbells right
these are really nice there's very
minimal plastic here as well these
plates are all steel and the adjustment
process is awesome so there's a red
button right here you just press it and
you just turn the dial and that's all
you got to do all you have to do and you
don't have to do both sides there's
other similar you know adjustable
dumbbells out there like these right
here but you have to adjust both sides I
really like how you don't have to do
that only drawback some people may have
with these is the rubber grip right here
it's fine it's going to give you a
pretty solid grip but I mean my opinion
nothing really compares to you know
having a fully knurled steel handle now
they do have an 88lb option if you want
you know a heavier and beefier build
these are not sold as a pairs though
they're individually and right now
they're right around 300 bucks but 400
bucks 66 lb this is a pretty solid
option for
[Music]
you okay so a lot of youall may be
wondering how exactly did you guys land
on these four adjustable dumbbells and
consider them to be the best options
that are on the market well similar to
any other equipment like a barbell or
whatever it is weight plates you name it
you got to worry about the money first
and foremost because you don't want to
really overspend right so I know the
Snows and the newo bells are both 800
bucks or so but you know the overall
quality which is my second Point makes
them worthy of that price tag and
they're still going to be cheaper than
purchasing a full set of traditional
dumbbells right now also for factoring
in the materials there's not a whole lot
of plastic used really in any of these
dumbbells right here and obviously the
ease of use I mean with the Neo Bells
you just simply twist like that with
Thea fits press this button in and twist
and with the Snows this right here now
the Nordic Track ones yes they take a
little bit longer than the other three
but all you got to do is just simply
lift up on that pin and and move it to
where you want to go it doesn't take
take very long for you to do it honestly
that's it that's the method to our
Madness and when it comes to finding you
know the best ones for you specifically
similar to any other equipment you need
to align your goals with your budget
right you don't want to overspend but
you really want to think about you know
where you currently are in your fitness
journey and then where you're kind of
going to go right so whether you're
looking for you know some starter
adjustable dumbbells to really get you
going or you're looking for something
heavier you know if you're more advanced
in your lifting phase you really can't
get wrong with any of these though at
the end of the
[Music]
day well that's a wrap for today's video
over the best adjustable dumbbells that
are on the market it's a short list yes
but they're the best available whether
you're a beginner looking for something
to get you going or you're looking for
some heavier weight you can't go wrong
like I said with any of these dumbbells
thanks for hanging out with me y'all I
hope this video was really helpful that
I was able to break down all of these
adjustable dumbbells and tell you all
the important information there is to
know as always stay on the lookout for
my next video but as I mentioned earlier
head over to barb. comom CU we have an
article that pairs with this video that
I definitely think you should check out
all you got to do is search barbend best
adjustable dumbbells and it's just going
to pull right up for you I'll catch
youall next
[Music]
time
he